..blind folded.
..se zavázanıma oèima.
But you have to keep your mind open like a scientist
Musíte mít ale otevøenou mysl
we have not yet found out the absolute truth.
e jsme ještì neobjevili úplnou pravdu.
We live in a relative world
ijeme v relativním svìtì,
and that's why we have problems.
a proto máme problémy.
So many problems we face today,
V tìchto dnech èelíme tolika problémùm,
ecological problems are there, drug problems, sickness, this, that.
máme tu ekologické problémy, problémy s drogami, choroby, tohle, tamto.
And as if we feel
A jako bychom cítili,
there is a kind of a destructive force that is working
e tu existuje jakási nièivá síla, která pracuje,
and we are really bothered,
dìláme si kvùli tomu opravdové starosti
some are frightened
a ti, kteøí rozumí tomu, k jaké devastaci mùe dojít,
The reason for all these problems
Pøíèina všech tìchto problémù
is very simple
je velmi jednoduchá,
and if we can just go
a pokud se podíváme
into the scriptures of all the religions,
do svatıch písem všech náboenství,
there is one common point about them.
všechna mají jeden spoleènı znak.
The common thing,
Jejich spoleènı znak
all of them have said in essence one thing,
- všechna øíkají v podstatì jednu vìc,
and they have said that you have to seek the eternal.
øíkají, e musíte hledat to, co je vìèné.
Seek the eternal!
Hledejte to, co je vìèné!
Not take it for granted that you have got it.
Nepovaujte za samozøejmost, e to máte.
Seek the eternal
Hledejte to, co je vìèné
and the transitory is to be used
a to, co je pøechodné, by se mìlo pouívat
in its own limitations and understanding.
pouze ve svıch omezeních a porozumìní.
Here we have gone wrong
Zde jsme se vydali špatnou cestou,
because we have worried too much about transitory things
protoe jsme se pøíliš strachovali o pøechodné vìci
and nothing about the eternal.
a vùbec jsme se nezajímali o to, co je vìèné.
The transitory things are transitory
Pøechodné vìci jsou pøechodné,
because it has got the build in quality of getting destroyed.
protoe v sobì mají zabudovanou vlastnost, e se znièí.
That's why they are transitory
Proto jsou pøechodné,
otherwise they would have been eternal.
protoe jinak by byly vìèné.
This build in quality in the transitory things
Tato zabudovaná vlastnost v pøechodnıch vìcech
brings in all kinds of problems.
pøináší všechny moné druhy problémù.
When we look at these problems
Kdy se podíváme na tyto problémy,
we have to look back and see
musíme se ohlédnout a vidìt,
that by seeking eternal, how the solution can come.
jak mùe pøijít øešení pomocí hledání vìèného.
It's said in all religions that you have to be born again.
Ve všech náboenstvích se øíká, e se musíte znovu narodit.
That means they have indicated that we have to have
To znamená, e naznaèují, e musíme mít
a more - greater dimension,
víc - širší rozmìr,
a more awakened state
stav, ve kterém jsme více probuzení,
or a greater dimension of awareness.
nebo vìtší rozmìr vìdomí.
Not that to certify yourself as "we are born again".
Neoznaèovat se jako „my jsme znovu narození“.
If you just want to certify yourself
Pokud se chcete pouze takto oznaèovat
and want to live in ignorance
a ít v ignoranci,
and a blind following another blind, is not going to work out.
kdy slepec následuje dalšího slepce, nevypracuje se to.
One has to accept that so far
Musíte pøijmout, e doposud
we have not found the absolute
jsme nenašli to, co je absolutní
and that to find that absolute
a pro nalezení tohoto absolutna
we have to actualize the second birth.
musí dojít k druhému zrození.
Is not some sort of an artificial baptism that is going to work out:
ádnı druh umìlého køtu to nevypracuje.
Our fathers were baptised and their fathers were baptised
Naši otcové byli pokøtìni a jejich otcové byli pokøtìni
and we have been baptised and baptised and baptised.
a nás køtili a køtili a køtili.
In every religion they have some sort of
V kadém náboenství mají nìjakı druh
an artificial method of baptism,
umìlého køtu,
whether it's Hindu, Christian, Muslims, everybody has.
a u jde o hinduisty, køesany, muslimy, všichni mají nìco.
But nobody has actualized
Ale nikdo z nich nepøinesl nic nového
and that actualization has to take place,
a tato obnova musí nastat,
for which the Creator must have
a kvùli ní musel Stvoøitel
created something great within us.
vytvoøit nìco velikého uvnitø nás.
When we see the civilisation outside
Kdy vidíme naši civilizaci,
and then we realize that there is something wrong in it,
uvìdomíme si, e je s ní nìco špatnì,
we have to know that this outside growths
musíme vìdìt, e tento vnìjší rùst
is like a tree growing outward.
je jako strom rostoucí smìrem ven.
But the roots must be nourished, we must know the roots.
Musí bıt ale vyivovány koøeny, musíme znát koøeny.
And this is the knowledge of the roots.
A toto je znalost o koøenech.
Now you have to take it as a hypotheses whatever I am saying to you.
Všechno, co øeknu, musíte teï brát jako hypotézu.
Not to take it for granted.
Neberte to jako samozøejmost.
It's a hypotheses.
Je to hypotéza.
If it works then in all your honesty you have to accept it.
Pokud to bude fungovat, musíte to ve vší upøímnosti pøijmout.
It is being said
Øíká se,
by Jung, has said it clearly
Jung to øekl zcela jasnì,
that you have to get your Self-realization
e musíte získat svou seberealizaci,
by which you will have collective consciousness,
díky kterému budete mít kolektivní vìdomí,
a new dimension to your awareness.
novı rozmìr vašeho vìdomí.
Or we say, we are all brothers, alright,
Také øíkáme, e jsme všichni bratøi - dobøe,
every country is one country, God has created one world,
všechny zemì jsou jedno, Bùh stvoøil jeden svìt,
they talk of United Nations and all that,
mluví o Organizaci spojenıch národù a o všech tìchto vìcech,
but they are not.
ale oni nejsou.
Let something happen and you will find
Kdy se nìco stane, zjistíte,
all of them are hither and thither.
e zaènou zmatkovat.
Why? Why it happens this way that we cannot
Proè? Proè to tak je, e nevidíme
see that unity in people who talk about it?
tuto jednotu v lidech, kteøí o ní mluví?
We cannot feel that peace about which they talk?
Proè nedokáeme cítit mír, o kterém hovoøí?
They have got peace foundations and
Mají mírové nadace
they have got all kinds of organisations,
a mají všechny druhy organizací,
talking of big, big things, but we don't find that
mluví o velkıch, velkıch vìcech, ale pøesto zjišujeme,
those who are running them have any peace within themselves.
e ti, kteøí je provozují, v sobì ádnı mír nemají.
So with unreal things we cannot create reality.
A pomocí zdánlivıch vìcí nemùeme vytváøet skuteènost.
Thus we have to realise that
Proto si musíme uvìdomit,
the time has come for us to take our second birth.
e nastal èas, abychom se podruhé narodili.
If we want to have any meaning to our life,
Pokud chceme, aby náš ivot mìl smysl,
to our human life, we have to have our second birth.
náš lidskı ivot, musíme se podruhé narodit.
If we cannot have our second birth
Pokud se nedokáeme podruhé narodit,
our life is a waste, it has no meaning.
mrháme svım ivotem, kterı nemá ádnou cenu.
Now the second birth is -
Tedy druhé narození je -
I would say that in India, in Sanskrit language
øekla bych, e v Indii, v sanskrtu,
we call a person who is twice born as "vijaha", is the born twice.
nazıváme podruhé narozenou osobu „vijaha“ - je podruhé narozená.
And the one who is born again also is called "vijaha",
A ten, kdo se znovu narodil, je také nazıván jako „vijaha“,
Self-realized. A person who is born again is "vijaha".
Seberealizovanı. Èlovìk, kterı se znovu narodil, je „vijaha“.
And also a bird is called as "vijaha",
Také ptákùm se øíká „vijaha“,
means the bird which is an egg first and it has a second birth
protoe pták byl nejprve vajíèkem a potom se podruhé narodil
and by that second birth he becomes the real bird.
a tímto druhım narozením se z nìj stává skuteènı pták.
First the egg and then the bird.
Nejdøív vajíèko, potom pták.
This kind of second birth
Tento druh druhého narození
has to actualize within us.
se musí odehrát uvnitø nás.
You try anything else - lecturing, sermoning,
Zkuste cokoli jiného - pøednášky, kázání,
doing all kinds of things that people do-
dìlejte všechny druhy vìcí, které lidé dìlají -
is not going to work out.
nebude to fungovat.
Because it's a living process of living energy of God.
Protoe tohle je ivı proces ivé energie Boha.
The living process works spontaneously, as like a seed,
ivı proces pracuje spontánnì, jako semínko,
you have to just put it in the Mother Earth and it sprouts by itself.
staèí ho jenom vloit do Matky Zemì a zaène klíèit samo od sebe.
It sprouts - you can't say how,
Klíèí - nedokáete øíci jak,
because the Mother Earth has got the potential
protoe v Matce Zemi je potenciál
and the seed has got the build in power.
a semínko má v sobì zabudovanou sílu.
In the same way we all are build in to be that.
Tím samım zpùsobem je to zabudováno i v nás.
Now Sahaja Yoga -" saha" means with, "ja" means with you is born -
Tedy Sahada jóga - „saha“ zna- mená s,  „ja“ znamená vrozená -
is the right to be united with the Divine Power
je to právo bıt sjednocen s Boskou silou,
which is all pervading.
která je všepronikající.
Now when I talk of all pervading power of divine love
A kdy mluvím o všepronikající síle Boské lásky,
people might say, Mother is talking something
lidé mohou øíkat, e Matka mluví o nìèem,
which we don't believe in.
v co nevìøíme.
You believe in it or not - it is so.
Vìøíte v to nebo ne - je to tak.
Now see these flowers, it's a miracle.
Podívejte se na tyto kvìtiny, je to zázrak.
We can't create even one!
My nedokáeme vytvoøit jedinou kvìtinu!
Who does this work?
Kdo dìlá tuto práci?
And the choice - the roses will have roses,
A ten vıbìr - rùe budou mít rùe,
jasmin will have jasmin,
jasmín bude mít jasmín,
chrysanthemums will have chrysanthemums.
chryzantémy budou mít chryzantémy.
Who does this choice?
Kdo dìlá tuto volbu?
Done by this divine power
Tato Boská síla,
which is very subtle and all pervading.
která je velmi jemná a všepronikající.
Only after realization you can feel that power
Pouze po získání realizace dokáete tuto sílu cítit
as cool breeze of the Holy Ghost
jako chladnı vánek Ducha svatého,
because that power is the Holy Spirit.
protoe tato síla je Duch svatı.
That power is the one which we call it in Sanskrit language
Tato síla je ta, kterou v sanskrtu nazıváme
as Brahmachaitanya.
Brahmaèajtanja.
That power acts and works out all these wonderful things.
Tato síla pùsobí a vypracovává všechny tyto úasné vìci.
Now in our evolutionary process we have reached the human stage.
V evoluèním procesu jsme dosáhli lidského stádia.
We have to go little further to achieve it.
Abychom toho dosáhli, musíme jít trochu dále.
It's a very easy thing to do,
Je to velmi jednoduché,
it can be easily done, takes hardly any time.
jde to udìlat velmi snadno a nezabírá to témìø ádnı èas.
And I have to say that no amount of arguments
A musím øíci, e ádné mnoství diskuzí
can bring forth this happening, it has to work out within yourself.
nemùe toto dìní vyvolat, musí se to vypracovat ve vás.
As a result of that you yourself in that enlightenment
V dùsledku toho sami znáte tolik vìcí
know so many things
v tomto osvícení,
and that in that enlightenment
a v tomto osvícení
you know what is the Absolute and what is not.
víte, co je absolutní a co ne.
In a way we can say, you become a saint.
Svım zpùsobem mùeme øíci, e se z vás stanou svìtci.
A saint, who doesn't give up his family, his houses, anything.
Svìtci, kteøí se nevzdají své rodiny, domù, èehokoli.
He lives as he has to live with his own status,
ijí, jak ve svém postavení ít musí,
with his own family life, with whatever it is.
se svou rodinou, se vším, a je to cokoli.
Supposing Christ was born in a rich family,
Kdyby se Kristus narodil v bohaté rodinì,
He would have lived like a king, in complete detachment.
il by jako král v naprosté odpoutanosti.
And if He was born in a poor family, as He was born,
A pokud by se narodil v chudé rodinì, jak to doopravdy bylo -
He lived like a carpenter's son.
On il jako syn tesaøe.
Because such a person has no attachment to things
Protoe taková osoba není k vìcem vùbec pøipoutaná
and is not bothered as to what is important to other people.
a nezatìuje se tím, co je dùleité pro jiné lidi.
What is the most important thing for such a person
Co je pro takovou osobu nejdùleitìjší,
is the benevolence of others.
je blaho ostatních.
He looks after the benevolence.
Stará se o jejich blaho.
And the benevolence is done not by money,
A toto blaho nevzniká penìzi,
by talking sweetly
nebo sladkou mluvou,
but actually through the power that He has
ve skuteènosti vzniká skrze schopnost vnímat vibrace,
of vibratory awareness.
kterou má.
Such a person has such innocent eyes
Takovı èlovìk má tak nevinné oèi,
that even a glance of that eye can do wonders.
e jedinı pohled tohoto oka dokáe zázraky.
Now through your Kundalini awakening
Tedy skrze probuzení Kundaliní
people have been cured definitely of cancer
se lidé úplnì vyléèili z rakoviny
and of so many diseases.
a z mnoha jinıch chorob.
And in Delhi University for your information there are three doctors
A pro vaši informaci, na univerzitì v Dillí jsou tøi doktoøi,
who have done their MD
kteøí získali svùj doktorát z medicíny
with the theses on three subjects:
pomocí závìreèné práce na tato tøi témata:
one with the physical abilities in Sahaja Yoga,
první s fyzickımi schopnostmi v Sahada józe,
second epilepsy cured by Kundalini awakening
druhı s epilepsií vyléèenou pomocí probuzení Kundaliní
and third for psychosomatic diseases.
a tøetí s psychoso- matickımi chorobami.
Psychosomatic diseases means
Psychosomatické choroby v sobì zahrnují
so many diseases which are supposed to be incurable
tolik chorob, které jsou povaovány za nevyléèitelné,
like Parkinson, cancer, aids.
jako je Parkinsonova choroba, rakovina, AIDS.
And they have got their MDs.
A tak získali doktorát z medicíny.
Now in America as you know there is a law that
Jak víte, v Americe existuje zákon,
nobody can cure without the permission of your associations.
e nikdo nesmí léèit bez povolení vašich asociací.
But you don't do anything.
Ale vy nedìláte nic.
Actually your Kundalini itself rises,
Ve skuteènosti vaše Kundaliní sama stoupá,
it's your own power that rises!
je to vaše vlastní síla, která stoupá!
And you get just cured.
A vy se prostì vyléèíte.
And how you get cured that I'll be telling you tomorrow,
A zítra vám øeknu, jak se vyléèíte,
how it works physically, mentally, emotionally and spiritually,
jak to funguje fyzicky, mentálnì, emocionálnì a duchovnì
and how you become a different personality,
a jak se z vás stane jinı èlovìk,
a special personality,
mimoøádná osobnost,
who is endowed with collective consciousness
která je obdaøena kolektivním vìdomím,
that you can feel the centres of another person and your own centres
která je schopna cítit centra jiné osoby a svá vlastní centra,
and that you can raise the Kundalini of another person.
která dokáe zvedat Kundaliní dalšímu èlovìku.
All these things can happen to you
Toto všechno se vám mùe pøihodit,
and you can become that powerful person
mùe se z vás stát tak silná osoba,
as been described in the scriptures.
jak bylo popsáno ve svatıch písmech.
So today for the time being
Take dnes prozatím
let us think of getting your realization.
zvate získání vaší seberalizace.
And tomorrow again I'll tell you how these diseases can be cured
A zítra vám tedy øeknu, jak mohou bıt vyléèeny tyto choroby,
if we can get these centres
pokud posílíme a vyivíme tato centra
enriched and nourished by Kundalini awakening.
probuzením Kundaliní.
Talking about Sahaja Yoga and Kundalini
Mluvit o Sahada józe a Kundaliní
is very easy and anybody can talk about it.
je velmi snadné a mùe to dìlat kadı.
But the main thing is to get your Self-realization.
Ale to nejdùleitìjší je získání seberealizace.
I must have spoken in various places
Musela jsem mluvit na rùznıch místech
and thousands of lectures I must have given.
a musela jsem udìlat tisíce pøednášek.
But that is of no avail because
Ale to je k nièemu, protoe
by lecturing you cannot get your realization.
pomocí pøednášek seberealizaci nezískáte.
There is no end to this knowledge
Toto poznání je nekoneèné,
but as for opening these lights you have to just switch on one light,
ale stejnì jako staèí stisknout jeden vypínaè
one switch,
pro rozsvícení tìchto svìtel,
in the same way it's all build in within you,
stejnım zpùsobem je to zabudováno ve vás.
only thing - you have to get it
Je to jediná vìc - musíte to získat
and you have to feel this all pervading power.
a musíte cítit tuto všepronikající sílu.
So now I think let's have the experience,
Myslím si, e teï bude nejlepší nápad
will be the best idea.
získat tuto zkušenost.
And if you have any questions
Pokud máte nìjaké otázky,
you may write them and give it to us.
mùete je sepsat a dát nám je.
Tomorrow I hope to answer all your questions.
Doufám, e zítra se mi podaøí všechny je zodpovìdìt.
So I hope you like to have your realization first.
Doufám tedy, e chcete nejprve získat seberealizaci.
Is it all right?
Je to tak v poøádku?
I think those people who are very much far away could come forward,
Myslím si, e lidé, kteøí jsou hodnì vzadu, by mohli pøijít blíe,
would be better idea, this side.
to bude nejlepší, na tuhle stranu.
Today is a very good day with Father's Day and
Dnešek je velmi dobrı den, Den otcù
is also the day of our Creator.
je den našeho Stvoøitele.
Anyone can come here just to show?
Mùe sem nìkdo pøijít ukazovat?
All right.
Dobøe.
You'll have to show where to put hands and things like that.
Musíš ukazovat, kam pokládat ruce a tak.
Is a very simple thing is that
Velmi jednoduchá vìc je,
first you have to take out your shoes
e si nejdøíve musíte sundat boty,
because Mother Earth helps us a lot to take out our problems.
protoe Matka Zemì nám velmi pomáhá tím, e z nás vytahuje naše problémy.
Now, it's a very simple method,
Je to velmi jednoduchá technika,
you don't have to do much.
nemusíte toho dìlat moc.
But on the very outset there is one condition
Ale hned na zaèátku existuje jedna podmínka,
that you have not to feel guilty about anything whatsoever.
nesmíte mít vùbec ádné pocity viny ohlednì èehokoli.
Forget the past and please don't feel guilty.
Zapomeòte na minulost a prosím, necite se provinile.
Please don't feel guilty.
Prosím, necite se vinni.
Forget the past.
Zapomeòte na minulost.
You have to be very pleasantly placed towards yourself
Musíte o sobì smıšlet velmi hezky,
because we have to enter into the Kingdom of God.
protoe musíme vstoupit do Království boího.
And we should not condemn ourselves.
A nemìli bychom se obviòovat.
After all we are human beings, we are not God.
Ostatnì, jsme lidské bytosti, nejsme Bùh.
And if we have done any mistakes
A pokud jsme se dopustili nìjakıch chyb,
the Divine Love has power to dissolve everything.
Boská láska má sílu to všechno rozpustit.
So please be pleasantly placed towards yourself.
Proto prosím, smıšlejte o sobì hezky.
Not to feel guilty is very important.
Je velmi dùleité nemít pocity viny.
And it's a fashion also these days
V souèasnosti je velmi moderní
just to feel guilty for nothing at all.
cítit se provinile pro nic za nic.
After all, if you have done something really serious
Konec koncù, pokud byste udìlali nìco opravdu váného,
we would be in jail, we would not have been here.
sedìli byste ve vìzení, nebyli byste tady.
So please do not judge yourself.
Proto prosím, neodsuzujte se.
Please do not judge yourself
Prosím, neodsuzujte se
and have that respect for yourself.
a vate si sami sebe.
Another request is that
Další podmínka je,
as we have to forget the past,
e musíte odpustit všem,
we have to forgive everyone.
protoe zapomenete na minulost.
That's something difficult I think.
Myslím si, e to je pomìrnì tìké.
In the west I found, wherever I had programs,
Zjistila jsem, e na Západì, kdekoli jsem mìla program,
every time I had to attend to them to see that they forgive.
vdycky jsem musela dohlédnout na to, aby všichni odpustili.
But logically, what do we do?
Ale logicky - co dìláme?
Wether we forgive or we don't forgive,
A u odpustíme èi nikoli,
we really don't do anything, do we?
ve skuteènosti nedìláme nic, nebo ano?
So why to
Tedy proè
go on pondering about something which bothers you?
pøemítat nad nìèím, co vás tak akorát zatìuje?
If you don't forgive then you play into wrong hands.
Pokud neodpustíte, nahráváte tím do nesprávnıch rukou.
So please try to forgive every one.
Proto prosím, pokuste se odpustit všem.
Just forgive, just a lip-service call it.
Prostì odpuste, úplnì jednoduše.
Just say, I forgive everyone.
Prostì øeknìte, odpouštím všem.
In your heart you have to say it.
Musíte to øíci ve svém srdci.
Please forgive.
Prosím, odpuste.
And don't remember whom you have to forgive.
A nepøemıšlejte nad tím, komu musíte odpustit.
Just take out that from your mind completely.
Úplnì to vypuste z mysli.
Let no such memory which makes you unhappy be there lingering.
Nedovolte ádné vzpomínce, která zpùsobuje,
All right.
Dobøe.
These are the only two things we have to do
Co se tıèe vašeho pøístupu,
as far as your own attitude is concerned.
toto jsou dvì jediné vìci, které musíte udìlat,
Now we have to know that it is all build in within us,
Musíte vìdìt, e všechno je ve vás zabudováno,
it's all your own and it will work out on its own.
je to vaše vlastní a samo se to vypracuje.
So
Take
we don't have to put in much effort, only thing,
nemusíte do toho vkládat pøíliš úsilí, jediné,
I would like to tell you how we can raise our own Kundalini
co bych vám chtìla øíci, je zpùsob,
and how
a jak
we have to release our own centres,
musíte vyèistit svá centra,
which is a very simple method, even a child can do it.
co je velmi jednoduché, dokonce i dítì to zvládne.
So first of all we have to put the left hand towards Me like this,
Ze všeho nejdøíve musíte dát levou ruku smìrem ke Mnì, takto,
because left hand is symbolically suggesting that
protoe levá ruka symbolicky naznaèuje,
we desire to have our Self-realization.
e si pøejeme získat seberealizaci.
So just put your left hand towards Me - all of you please do it.
Proto pouze polote svou levou ruku
Just put your left hand towards Me.
Pouze dejte levou ruku ke Mnì.
And put both the feet on the ground separately
A obì nohy polote, kadou zvláš, na zem,
because these are two powers, left and right power,
protoe toto jsou dvì síly, levá a pravá síla,
which I will tell you tomorrow exactly what it is.
o kterıch vám øeknu zítra, co to pøesnì je.
Now, put your left hand just like this.
Teï polote levou ruku takto.
And the right hand represents the action.
A pravá strana pøedstavuje akci.
So with the right hand we have to
Tedy pravou rukou se musíme
touch our different centres,
dotıkat našich rùznıch center,
just to release any blockade if there is.
abychom uvolnili všechny pøípadné bloky.
First thing will be to put your right hand on your heart.
Nejdøíve polote pravou ruku na srdce.
This I am showing you just now
Nyní vám to ukáu,
and then we'll have to close our eyes and do the same thing.
potom budete muset zavøít oèi a udìlat to samé.
So first is to put your hand on your heart.
Tedy nejdøíve polote pravou ruku na srdce.
This is the centre where resides the Spirit.
Toto je centrum, kde pøebıvá Duch.
The Spirit - Atma.
Duch - Átma.
Now you have to put down your right hand
Nyní polote pravou ruku níe,
in the upper portion of your stomach
na levou èást bøicha.
on the left hand side. We are working on the left hand side.
Pracujeme na levé stranì.
So put it on the left hand side,
Proto ji polote na levou stranu,
your right hand.
pravou ruku.
This is the centre of your mastery,
Toto je centrum vašeho mistrovství,
mastery which is created by many prophets,
mistrovství, které je vytvoøeno mnoha proroky,
by which you master the art of divine love,
kterım ovládnete umìní boské lásky,
by which you become your own master.
díky které se stanete svımi vlastními mistry.
Then you have to take this hand
Potom musíte tuto ruku pøesunout
in the lower part of the abdomen on the left hand side.
na levou stranu podbøišku.
And here
A tady
is the centre of pure knowledge,
leí centrum èistého vìdìní,
pure knowledge that manifests
èistého vìdìní, které se projevuje
through your central nervous system.
skrze váš centrální nervovı systém.
It becomes your own knowledge
Stane se vaším vlastním vìdìním,
as you can feel cold, hot
protoe budete cítit chlad, horko,
you can feel the good and bad.
budete vnímat dobré a špatné.
Then again you have to take back your hand
Potom opìt musíte pøesunout ruku
onto the upper portion of the abdomen,
na bøicho
and then again to your heart.
a znovu na srdce.
Then you have to take your right hand
Potom musíte poloit pravou ruku
in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
na ohyb krku a ramene
and place it
a umístit ji
as much as possible
jak jen to bude moné,
towards the spinal cord.
smìrem k páteøi.
And turn your head to your right.
A otoète hlavu doprava.
This centre catches when we feel guilty.
Stav tohoto centra zhoršují pocity viny.
And which is a very dangerous thing
A to je velmi nebezpeèné,
because by this centre blocked
protoe pokud je toto centrum v nepoøádku,
we get horrible diseases like angina,
mùeme dostat takové hrozné nemoci, jako je angína,
spondylitis and all kinds of negative thoughts come into our mind.
spondylitida a také se tak do naší mysli dostávají negativní myšlenky.
So please put your right hand on
Proto prosím polote pravou ruku
the corner of your neck and your shoulder
na ohyb ramene a krku
and turn your head to your right.
a natoète hlavu doprava.
Now
Nyní
put your right hand on top of your forehead across
polote pravou ruku pøes èelo,
and bend your head and press it on both the sides.
skloòte hlavu a zatlaète na obì strany.
This is the centre of forgiveness.
Toto je centrum odpuštìní.
Now, take your right hand and put it back
Nyní pøesuòte pravou ruku dozadu,
on the backside of your head.
na zátylek.
And put your head on it to rest,
A polote do ní hlavu,
take it upward.
zakloòte ji.
This is the centre where you have to ask for forgiveness
Na tomto místì musíte ádat o odpuštìní
without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes.
bez pocitù viny, ani byste poèítali své chyby.
Then you have to stretch your hand fully.
Potom napnìte ruku.
Now stretch your hand please.
Teï napnìte ruku prosím.
The centre of your palm
A støed dlanì
you have to put it on top of
polote na vrchol hlavy
the soft bone which you had in your childhood,
na místo, které jste mìli v dìtství mìkké,
called as the fontanel bone area.
takzvanou oblast fontanely.
Press it hard,
Silnì zatlaète,
push back your fingers,
propnìte prsty,
put down your head
skloòte hlavu
and move your scalp seven times clockwise, very slowly.
a zakrute kùí na hlavì sedmkrát
That's all.
To je vše.
Very slowly you have to move it.
Musíte krouit velmi pomalu.
Seven times.
Sedmkrát.
That's all we have to do. Now please close your eyes.
To je vše, co musíte udìlat. Teï prosím zavøete oèi.
You can take out your spectacles. Be comfortable and
Mùete si sundat brıle. Pohodlnì se usaïte,
don't open your eyes please 'till I tell you
a dokud vám neøeknu, neotevírejte oèi,
because your attention has to be sucked in.
protoe vaše pozornost musí smìøovat dovnitø.
So please don't open your eyes.
Proto prosím, neotevírejte oèi.
There will be no problem,
Nenastane ádnı problém,
there will be
nebude se
no funny happening as some people fear,
dít nic smìšného, jak se nìkteøí lidé bojí,
is absolutely the smooth moving of the Kundalini
je naprosto jemnı pohyb Kundaliní,
'till you will start feeling the cool breeze
dokud nezaènete cítit chladnı vánek
coming out of your fontanel bone area.
vycházející z oblasti fontanely.
And also you will start feeling
Také zaènete cítit
this all pervading power of cool breeze.
tuto všepronikající sílu chladného vánku.
This is the beginning
Toto je zaèátek,
but later on we'll have to make this connection all right.
ale pozdìji budeme muset dát toto spojení do poøádku.
So please put your left hand towards Me
Tedy prosím, dejte ruku smìrem ke Mnì
and close your eyes
a zavøete oèi
and put the right hand on your heart.
a polote pravou ruku na srdce.
Here
Tady
you have to say within your heart,
si ve svém srdci musíte øíci,
or you have to ask Me a very fundamental question,
nebo se zeptejte Mì na velmi dùleitou otázku.
you may call Me Shri Mataji or Mother, whatever suits you.
Mùete mi øíkat Šrí Mátadí nebo Matko, jakkoli vám to vyhovuje.
Please ask the question three times,
Prosím, zeptejte se tøikrát:
Mother, am I the Spirit?
„Matko, jsem Duch?“
Please ask this question three times.
Prosím, zeptejte se tøikrát.
Now if you are the Spirit,
A pokud jste Duch,
also you are your master, you are your guide.
jste také svùj vlastní mistr, svùj vlastní prùvodce.
So please take down your hand onto the upper portion of your abdomen
Proto prosím pøesuòte pravou ruku na bøicho
and press it hard.
a silnì zatlaète.
Here again ask Me a question three times,
Tady se Mne opìt tøikrát zeptejte:
Mother, am I my own master?
„Matko, jsem svım vlastním mistrem?“
Ask this question three times.
Polote tuto otázku tøikrát.
Now take down your hand in the lower portion of your abdomen,
Teï pøesuòte ruku na podbøišek
on the left hand side.
na levé stranì.
Here is the centre of pure knowledge.
Zde se nachází centrum èistého vìdìní.
But I cannot force on you.
Nemohu vás ale nutit.
I respect your freedom.
Respektuji vaši svobodu.
In your freedom and glory you have to ask for it.
Musíte o to poádat ve své svobodì a slávì.
So please say,
Tedy prosím øeknìte:
Mother, please give me pure knowledge.
„Matko, prosím, dej mi èisté vìdìní.
I want pure knowledge.
Pøeji si mít èisté vìdìní.“
You have to ask for it.
Musíte o to poádat.
Say it six times
Øeknìte to šestkrát,
because this centre has got six petals.
protoe toto centrum má šest okvìtních lístkù.
Now, when you say that,
Bìhem toho, co to øíkáte,
your Kundalini starts moving upwards
vaše Kundaliní zaèíná stoupat
and so we have to now open the higher centres.
a proto musíme otevøít centra, která se nacházejí vıše.
So raise your hand, right hand,
Proto zvednìte ruku, pravou ruku,
and put it in the upper part of the abdomen and press it hard.
a polote ji na bøicho a silnì zatlaète.
Now here
Zde nyní
we have to help to open this centre.
musíme pomoci tomuto centru, aby se otevøelo.
So with full confidence you say ten times,
Proto s naprostou sebejistotou øeknìte desetkrát,
with full confidence you have to say ten times,
musíte naprosto sebejistì øíci desetkrát:
Mother, I am my own master. Please say it.
„Matko, jsem svım vlastním mistrem.“ Prosím, øeknìte to.
Mother, I am my own master.
Matko, jsem svım vlastním mistrem.
Now raise your hand
Teï zvednìte ruku
on your heart
na srdce,
which is the most important
kde se nachází to nejdùleitìjší centrum,
centre because the Spirit resides in it.
protoe v nìm pøebıvá Duch.
You are not this body,
Nejste toto tìlo,
you are not this mind,
nejste tato mysl,
you are not this intellect,
nejste tento intelekt,
you are not the conditioning,
nejste tyto pøedsudky,
you are not your ego,
nejste toto ego,
but you are pure Spirit.
jste èistı Duch.
So here you ask,
Tady se zeptejte,
twelve times you have to say it here,
tady to musíte øíci dvanáctkrát,
with full confidence twelve times,
dvanáctkrát s naprostou sebejistotou,
The greatest truth about yourself,
tu nejvìtší pravdu o sobì:
Mother, I am the Spirit.
„Matko, jsem Duch.
We have to know that the Divine is the ocean
Musíte vìdìt, e Boské je oceán
of love and compassion.
lásky a milosrdenství.
It is the ocean of bliss and joy.
Je to oceán blaha a radosti.
But above all
Ale pøedevším,
it is the ocean of forgiveness.
je to oceán odpuštìní.
So we cannot commit any mistakes
Nemùete se dopustit chyb,
which cannot be dissolved by this great ocean of forgiveness.
které nelze rozpustit v oceánu odpuštìní.
So please raise your right hand in the corner of your
Pøesuòte pravou ruku na ohyb ramene a krku
shoulder and your neck and press it hard.
a silnì zatlaète.
Turn your head to the right.
Hlavu natoète doprava.
Here with full confidence please say sixteen times, sixteen times,
Tady s naprostou sebejistotou øeknìte šestnáctkrát, šestnáctkrát:
Mother, I am not guilty.
„Matko, já nejsem nièím vinen.“
Please have confidence in yourself
Prosím, mìjte v sebe dùvìru
and say it, Mother I'm not guilty.
a øeknìte to: „ Matko, já nejsem nièím vinen.“
All these ideas that you are a sinner, you are this,
Všechny ty názory, e jste høíšníci, e jste tohle,
please forget it! That's all nonsense!
prosím, zapomeòte na to! Je to celé nesmysl!
You are a human being
Jste lidská bytost
and you have to become a Self-realized personality.
a musíte se stát seberealizo- vanımi osobnostmi.
That's what it is.
Tak to je.
So please say sixteen times, Mother, I' not guilty at all.
Proto prosím øeknìte šestnáctkrát: „Matko, nejsem vùbec nièím vinen.“
As I have told you that
Jak jsem vám ji øekla,
whether we forgive or don't forgive,
a u odpustíte èi nikoli,
we do not do anything. It's just a myth.
nic nedìláte. Je to jen mıtus.
So we should forgive
Proto byste mìli odpustit,
because if we don't forgive we play into wrong hands
protoe pokud neodpustíte, nahráváte tím do špatnıch rukou
because of this myth.
kvùli tomuto mıtu.
We think that we have not forgiven,
Myslíme si, e jsme neodpustili,
how can we forgive, it is rather difficult.
jak mùeme odpustit - je to pomìrnì tìké.
But there is nothing difficult about it.
Ale není na tom vùbec nic sloitého.
Now please raise your right hand
Nyní prosím polote pravou ruku
onto your forehead across,
pøes èelo,
place it across and bend it down
polote ji pøes èelo a skloòte hlavu
and press it on both the sides.
a zatlaète na obou stranách.
Here is the centre where you have to forgive.
Zde je centrum, kde musíte odpustit.
So please from your heart,
Proto prosím, z celého srdce,
please from your heart forgive everyone.
z celého srdce prosím odpuste všem.
Please from your heart, otherwise it doesn't work out,
Prosím, z celého srdce, jinak se to nevypracuje,
Realization doesn't work out,
nedostanete seberealizaci,
the Kundalini stops at this centre which is very important.
Kundaliní se u tohoto centra, které je velmi dùleité, zastaví.
Please, please forgive!
Prosím, prosím, odpuste!
Forgive everyone, I request you again and again,
Odpuste všem, ádám vás znovu a znovu,
please forgive everyone, very important!
prosím, odpuste všem, velmi dùleité!
That's the biggest blockade I think, I faced.
Myslím si, e to je nejvìtší pøekáka, které jsem èelila.
Now, take back your hand and put it on the backside of your head
Nyní pøesuòte ruku na zátylek
and push your head on it.
a polote do ní hlavu.
Here now you have to say,
Tady musíte øíci:
O Divine if I have done any mistakes, please forgive!
„Ó, Boské, pokud jsem se dopustil nìjakıch chyb, prosím, odpus mi.“
But you are not to feel guilty,
Ale bez pocitù viny,
you are not to count your mistakes. It's for your satisfaction.
nepoèítejte své chyby. Je to pro vaše uspokojení.
Just say, If I have done any mistakes, please forgive!
Prostì øeknìte: „Pokud jsem se dopustil
From your heart, how many times is not the point.
Ze srdce - není dùleité kolikrát.
Now stretch your hand please,
Teï prosím propnìte ruku,
put left hand towards Me.
levou ruku polote smìrem ke Mnì.
Stretch your hand and the centre of your palm
Propnìte ruku a opatrnì prosím polote støed dlanì
please carefully put it on the fontanel bone area
na oblast fontanely,
or the soft bone which you had in your childhood.
nebo také na místo, které bylo ve vašem dìtství mìkké.
The centre of your palm.
Støed dlanì.
Push back your fingers as much as you can.
Propnìte prsty co nejvíc.
And now you have to move your scalp very slowly,
A nyní pohybujte velmi pomalu kùí na hlavì,
very slowly clockwise,
velmi pomalu, ve smìru hodinovıch ruèièek,
very slowly clockwise seven times.
velmi pomalu, ve smìru hodinovıch ruèièek, sedmkrát.
Here again I cannot force Self-realization.
Tady vám opìt nemohu seberealizaci vnutit.
I cannot force that on you.
Nemohu vám to vnutit.
So you have to say,
Proto musíte øíci:
Mother please give me my Self-realization.
„Matko, prosím, dej mi mou seberealizaci.“
I cannot disrespect your freedom.
Nemohu obejít vaši svobodu.
So please say it seven times, moving your hand very slowly,
Proto to prosím øeknìte sedmkrát, rukou krute velmi pomalu,
pressing your scalp, moving your scalp,
tlaète na hlavu, krute kùí na hlavì,
pressing back your fingers. Please do it carefully!
s propnutımi prsty. Dìlejte to prosím opatrnì!
(Shri Mataji blows into the micro).
(Šrí Matadí fouká do mikrofonu.)
Now please take down your hands
Nyní prosím polote ruce zpìt
and open your eyes.
a otevøete oèi.
Just watch Me without thinking - you can do it!
Bez pøemıšlení se na Mì dívejte - mùete to udìlat!
Just watch Me without thinking.
Pouze se na Mì dívejte, bez pøemıšlení.
Now put the right hand like this and bend your head
Nyní dejte pravou ruku takto a skloòte hlavou
and see for yourself
a vyzkoušejte,
if there is a cool breeze coming out of your head.
zda cítíte chladnı vánek vycházející z vaší hlavy.
Some people might feel a little heat coming out,
Nìkteøí lidé mohou cítit trochu vycházejícího tepla,
it's all right because heat has to come out first.
to je v poøádku, protoe teplo musí odejít jako první.
Now put your left hand towards Me, bend your head
Teï polote ruku smìrem ke Mnì, skloòte hlavu
and see for yourself if there is a cool breeze coming out.
a vyzkoušejte, zda odtud vychází chladnı vánek.
It's already very much cooled down, but don't doubt it, just feel.
U se to velmi zchladilo, ale nepo- chybujte o tom, jenom vnímejte.
Sometimes it comes quite ahead
Nìkdy to vychází pomìrnì vpøedu,
but try to put it next to your head
ale pokuste se ji dát k hlavì,
but not on top,  above it
ale ne na vrchol, nad nìj,
and then move further to see if there is a cool breeze coming out.
a potom jí zvedejte vıš, a vnímejte, zda vychází chladnı vánek.
Now put back your right hand please.
Nyní vrate pravou ruku zpátky prosím.
And see for yourself again if there is a cool breeze coming out of.
A znovu vyzkoušejte, zda vychází chladnı vánek.
Don't get upset if it is not there, it will work out.
Nebuïte zklamaní, pokud to necítíte, vypracuje se to.
Don't get upset, just watch!
Nezneklidòujte se, jenom pozorujte!
Now push back, push back your hands like this towards the sky,
Nyní zvednìte, zvednìte takto ruce k nebi,
push back your head.
zakloòte hlavu.
And here you ask a question three times,
A tady se tøikrát zeptejte,
anyone of these questions:
polote jednu z tìchto otázek:
Mother, is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?
„Matko, je toto chladnı vánek Ducha svatého?
Mother, is this the all pervading power of Divine Love?
Matko, je toto všepronikající síla Boské lásky?
Mother, is this the Brahmachaitanya?
Matko, je toto Brahmaèantajna?“
Ask this question three times.
Polote tuto otázku tøikrát.
Anyone of them, just ask it three times.
Jakoukoli z nich, pouze ji tøikrát polote.
Now take down your hands please.
Teï vrate ruce zpìt prosím.
Now see, there is no breeze around.
Vidíte, nefouká ádnı vítr.
The trees are silent, they are just watching us.
Stromy jsou potichu, jen nás sledují.
But you'll feel the breeze in your hand
Ale vy v ruce cítíte vánek
and you must have felt the breeze out of your head also.
a také jste jistì cítili vánek vycházející z hlavy.
Those who have felt cool breeze coming out of their head,
Ti z vás, kteøí jste cítili chladnı vánek vycházející z hlavy,
the fontanel bone area or from your fingertips,
z oblasti fontanely nebo z koneèkù prstù,
will you please raise your both the hands?
mùete prosím zvednout obì ruce?
Please raise higher!
Zvednìte je vıš prosím!
O my God!
Ach, Mùj Boe!
Practically the whole of San Diego has felt it!
V podstatì celé San Diego to cítilo!
Tremendous place! Thank you, thank you!
Ohromné místo! Dìkuji vám, dìkuji!
May God bless you!
A vám Bùh ehná!
Now don't discuss about it because it is beyond thought.
Neprobírejte to spolu, protoe je to mimo myšlenky.
You are in thoughtless awareness.
Jste v bezmyšlenkovém vìdomí.
But tomorrow when you will come then we'll again see about it,
Ale zítra, a se vrátíte, znovu se na to zamìøíme,
as I would say, the connection has to be properly fixed.
abych tak øekla, spojení se musí poøádnì upevnit.
For that tomorrow you'll be here
Proto tu zítra budete
and I hope there will be a follow on program.
a také doufám, e bude navazující program.
One must know that you cannot pay for it.
Musíte vìdìt, e za toto nemùete platit.
One must know that you cannot think about it.
e o tom nelze pøemıšlet.
It just happens and is there.
Prostì se to dìje a je.
So enjoy this night and every night
Uijte si tuto noc a kadou noc
and every moment of your life!
a kadou chvíli v ivotì!
May God bless you! May God bless you all!
A vám Bùh ehná! A vám všem ehná Bùh!
What does he say?
Co øíká?
They should write it down, questions later, tomorrow morning,
A to sepíší, otázky probereme pozdìji, zítra ráno,
tomorrow when we come
a zítra pøijdeme,
because today what I am saying that let them go home,
protoe, jak øíkám, a jdou dnes domù,
tomorrow let them come and  then we'll see about it.
a a se zítra vrátí, uvidíme.
Today let them go.
Nechte je dnes jít.
So I would say tonight you can go home, just stressed.
Proto navrhuji, abyste šli domù, jen zdùrazòuji,
Don't talk about it, just be in silence.
nemluvte o tom, buïte v tichosti.
This is the thing you have been seeking, which has happened,
Právì se stalo nìco, co jste hledali,
it has worked out but
a ono se to vypracovalo,
we have to understand each and every thing about it,
ale musíte pochopit všechno, co s tím souvisí,
the whole knowledge will be given to you.
dostane se vám veškerého vìdìní.
Absolutely you will know the whole thing.
Budete znát celou záleitost.
And tomorrow I'll be meeting you, people,
A zítra se s vámi setkám,
I will give much more time,
strávím s vámi více èasu,
I will start much more earlier in a proper way.
zaènu mnohem døíve a správnım zpùsobem.
I hope you enjoy this new life
Doufám, e si uijete tento novı ivot,
which is starting now
kterı vám nyní zaèíná
and the transformation that will take place,
a promìnu, která se odehraje.
you'll be amazed at yourself! Complete transformation!
Budete sebou ohromeni! Naprostá promìna!
Tomorrow we'll talk about it more.
Zítra o tom budeme mluvit více.
May God bless you all!
A vám všem Bùh ehná!
Now inform your friends and call them here
Øeknìte o tom svım pøátelùm a pozvìte je,
and let them also receive this Self-realization.
a také získají seberealizaci.
It is your own and you all should have it.
Patøí vám to a všichni byste to mìli mít.
You have a right to have it.
Máte na to právo.
So may God bless you all!
Tedy a vám všem ehná Bùh!